MILAN KACAR

Software & Survey Engineer



ABOUT ME

I am a Software Engineer & Survey Engineer with 5+ years of professional experience. I graduated Geodesy at Graz University of Technology in Austria, where I worked as a project and teaching assistant. Currently, I am working in the e-commerce & fintech industry for Niceshops GmbH and Gateway Ventures GmbH as a Data Scientist / Engineer / Analyst. I grew up in Mrkonjic Grad (Republic of Srpska, BA) where I finished high school with Mathematics, Logic, and Physics at a Higher Level.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Late of birth	01.09.1995
Birthplace	Banja Luka, BA
Citizenship	Austrian
Marital status	Single
♥ Sex	Male

EDUCATION

BSc Geomatics Engineering	
University of Technology, TU Graz	

Master's Degree Programme - Geodesy University of Technology, TU Graz

Master's Degree Programme - Computer Science University of Technology, TU Graz

WORK AND PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Data Integration & ETL Pipelines Manage data integration and ETL pipelines, ensuring high-quality data processing and governance for analytics and reporting at Niceshops GmbH and Gateway Ventures.
- Data Lake & Warehouse Management Led the development of a data lake at Gateway Ventures and currently maintain the data warehouse at Niceshops GmbH, optimizing data storage and accessibility.
- Forecasting & Business Analytics Analyze trends, forecast demand, and optimize business performance by integrating data from Google Analytics, Facebook, TikTok, and in-house sources.
- Automated Reporting & Dashboards Develop automated reports and dashboards in Looker and other platforms to support CEOs and departments with data-driven decision-making.
- Anomaly Detection & Pattern Recognition Identify inefficiencies, detect anomalies, and improve business operations by recognizing patterns in large datasets.
- Personal Blog on Programming, Al, Math, and Finance Share insights on Al, mathematics, finance, and LeetCode challenges through technical articles and problem-solving discussions.

TECHNICAL STRENGTH

Python	•••••
Google Cloud	•••••
C/C++	•••••
GIS	•••••
PostgreSQL	•••••
AWS	•••••
Navigation	•••••
GNSS	•••••
Signal Processing	•••••
Java	••••
Data Structures & Algorithms	•••••
MySQL	•••••
Docker	•••••
Java Script	••••
PHP	••••
Linux	•••••
R	••••
Apache Spark	•••••
Kubernetes	•••••
Databricks	••••
Scala	••••

DISSERTATION WORK

BSc Thesis

Database for cycling routes

- Entity Relationship Diagram.
- Building the Database.
- Conversion from analog to digital maps.

MSc Thesis

PV (Photovoltaic) panels detection from satellite images

- Project uses AI (Artificial intelligence) and ML (Machine learning) as a hybrid approach to detect panels.
- Building an independent model to work on different datasets.
- Cloud computing
- YOLOv5

WORK EXPERIENCE

Survey Engineer **GEODATA**

July 2019 - December 2020

Semmering Basistunnel, Austria

Tunnel surveying | 3D Laser scanner measurements

Teaching Assistant

TU Graz

March 2021 - January 2022

Graz, Austria

Integrated navigation | Sensor fusion | Indoor navigation

Software Engineer

TU Graz

🛗 Sep 2019 - January 2022

Graz, Austria

Software Architect | Project Management | Automation | Data Analysis | ML Forecasting | Statistics | Automotive Battery and Electric Vehicle Testing

Data Scientist & Data Engineer niceshops GmbH

Vienna, Austria

Finances (all types of tasks) analysis | Data Engineering | Large scale data crawling | Cloud computing | GCP | Looker | AI & ML tasks | Courses inside the house / teaching (Looker) | Research about demand forecasting |

Data Engineer / TL

Gateway Ventures GmbH

August 2023 - pending

Vienna, Austria

Startup Founding | Startup Valuation models | Pitch Deck Analyzer | Tinder for Investors/Startups | Data Lake construction | Data Mining | Data Scraping | Project Management | Investor matchmaking tool

STRENGTHS

Hard-working Decision Making

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Motivator & Leader

Conflict Resolution

Time Management

Target oriented

Able to travel

Flexibility and Adaptability

Problem solver

LANGUAGES

Serbian | Croatian | Bosnian **English** German

Russian



HOBBIES



Reading

I am trying to read a book per week.



Sports Addict

At a young age I enjoyed playing tennis, but my interests migrated towards Fitness and healthy food.



Travelling

After living in a rustic, small town for the past 18 years, I was craving change and adventure. Ten years later, I've traveled to more places during college than the first two decades of my life.



Trading

I love to analyze the markets and factors that may impact the price on daily/weekly and long term basis.